<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<documentation>
	<page title="Organic Data Science Framework Documentation">
		<content>
			This page documents how to use the organic data science framework in an effective manner. The documentation is split into the following parts:<br />
			<table>
				<tr>
					<td>[[File:Docu_Participant.png|50px]]</td>
					<td style="vertical-align:middle">
						'''[[Contribute as Participant]]''' <br/>
						Here you can learn to browse tasks in different ways and to contribute to existing tasks.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>[[File:Docu_Owner.png|50px]]</td>
					<td style="vertical-align:middle">
						'''[[Contribute as Owner]]''' <br/>
						Here you can learn to create new tasks and organize them over time.	
					</td>
				</tr>				
			</table>						
		</content>
		<subpages>
			<page title="Contribute as Participant">	
				<content>
					This page documents how you can use the wiki as participant. The documentation is constitutive split into the following sub-pages:
					<table>
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_Exploring.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Exploring Tasks]]'''  <br/>
								Here you can learn to navigate and search for tasks.
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_Participating.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Participating on Tasks]]'''  <br/>
								Here you can learn to add yourself as participant to tasks and to contribute to them.	
							</td>
						</tr>	
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_PersonPage.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Person Page]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn to find relevant information on contributors. This includes the tasks they are involved with and their expertise.
							</td>
						</tr>	
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_States.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Basic Task States]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn the basics of how to manage task states.
							</td>
						</tr>	
					</table>					
				</content>
				<subpages>
					<page title="Exploring Tasks">
						<content>
						The Organic Data Science wiki framework enables scientists to collaborate in new ways doing what we call “task-oriented collaboration”.  
						The wiki poses some broad overarching science questions that cut across disciplines and institutions.  Answering those questions requires 
						contributors to formulate and collaborate in a variety of tasks through the ODS framework, such as decomposing the high level questions 
						into smaller tasks, sharing datasets, describing data characteristics, preparing them, and running models.  Therefore, a major aspect of 
						the framework is to understand how tasks work.  Several top-level tasks are formulated to capture the driving science questions, each with 
						subtasks which have other subtasks in turn<br/><br/>	
						
						Tasks of the organic data science framework can be browsed in many different ways. 
						Depending on your purpose you can choose between the '''[[#Task Explorer|task explorer]]''', the '''[[#Subtask Explorer|subtask explorer]]''' 
						and the '''[[#Timeline Explorer|timeline explorer]]'''. The best choice to browse within all tasks is the '''[[#Task Explorer|task explorer]]''', which appears on the left side of the screen. 
						In case you want to browse subtasks of a certain task you should use the '''[[#Subtask Explorer|subtask explorer]]'''. 
						Alternatively you can use the '''[[#Timeline Explorer|timeline explorer]]''' to browse subtasks and see their time dependencies. 
						The following figure illustrates these three different task browsing options. <br/><br/>						
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_Overview.png|600px|Exploring Tasks Overview]]
						
						==Task Explorer==
					The Task Explorer appears on the left of the screen.  It shows all tasks in the wiki organized in a tree hierarchy, with subtasks indented. This Task Explorer works comparable with the file browser in a desktop. 
						By default all top level task are visible. Every task with a 
						small triangle has at least one subtask, and can be expanded with a left mouse click on the triangle. 
						The wiki page for any task can be opened with a single left mouse click on the task name. 
						
						===All Tasks Tab===
						This tab of the Task Explorer shows all existing tasks in the wiki. You can use this to explore tasks within the wiki.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_AllTaskTab.png|200px]]
						
						===My Tasks Tab===
						This tab of the Task Explorer shows all tasks that you own. All other tasks are invisible or greyed out. Parent tasks which are needed to 
						represent the task hierarchy are greyed out. A red counter behind the tab label indicates how many tasks you have currently assigned to you as owner. 
						The [[#My Tasks Tab|My Tasks tab]] is only visible for users who are logged in. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_MyTaskTab.png|200px]]
						
						===Task Name Search===
						The Task Name Search allows you to search the task names. You can apply this search either 
						to the [[#All Tasks Tab|All Tasks tab]] or the [[#My Tasks Tab| My Tasks tab]]. All matching results are shown in the Task Explorer. 
						Parent tasks of matching tasks are shown but faded, just to provide context. <br/><br/>					
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_TextSearch.png|200px]]
						
						===Expertise Filter===
						The Expertise Filter works similar to the [[#Task Name Search|Task Name Search]], but it searches for tasks that are marked with the expertise indicated. 
						It offers a pull-down menu with the kinds of expertise already defined in the wiki.  
						The pull-down menu shows in brackets a number that indicates how many tasks have that expertise. After 
						selecting a certain expertise, the matching tasks are shown. The [[#Task Name Search| Task Name Search]] and the 
						[[#Expertise Filter|Expertise Filter]] can be combined. If both are applied, all results shown will match both criteria. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_ExpertiseFilter.png|200px]]
						
						===Hierarchical View and List View===
						The Task Explorer can show two different views of the tasks: the '''hierarchical view''' 
						and the '''list view'''. The hierarchical view shows the task-subtask hierarchy, and is the default view. 
						Furthermore the amount of tasks is smaller due to the nested task structure. 
						The list view does not show a parent or subtask hierarchy. The list view is more convenient when the hierarchy view shows a lot of faded tasks.<br/><br/>	 
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_View.png|420px]]
						
						===Resizing===
						Some task names are only partially shown because they are simply too long. Therefore you can resize the width of the Task Explorer. 
						Hover the mouse over the blue rectangle with the white arrows to the left and right. After that, '''left click''', then 
						'''hold''' and then '''move to the left''' or '''move to the right'''.<br/><br/>				
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_Resizing.png|250px]]
						
						==Subtask Explorer==
						The [[#Subtask Explorer| Subtask Explorer]] is basically to browse subtasks of the task currently opened in the wiki page. 
						The name of the current task shown in the wiki page is larger and the task icon is more detailed 
						with a number that indicates the percentage of the task that is completed (this will be explained later).  
						Above the current task name, the '''parent task''' is shown if there is one.
						Below it, all its '''subtasks''' are listed and can be expanded.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_SubtaskExplorer.png|550px]]
						
						==Timeline Explorer==
						The [[#Timeline Explorer|timeline explorer]] can be opened with a click on the blue '''Timeline''' tab on the top right. 
						Similar to the [[#Subtask Explorer| subtask explorer]], all subtasks of the current task are shown. The Timeline Explorer
						shows all subtasks in a time context comparable to a Gantt chart. The x-axis represents the time, and each bar shows a subtask. A number within 
						a bar represents the progress of that subtask. Today's date is marked with a vertical red line. Every task can be 
						opened with a simple click.	<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Exploring_TimelineExplorer.png|550px]]
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Participating on Tasks">
						<content>
						This page documents how you can be a participant in any task with only few simple steps. Once you '''[[#Add yourself as participant|add yourself as a task participant]]''',
						you can start '''[[#Add Content|to add content]]'''. After you have added content you can '''[[#Set Progress|set the progress]]''' on the task so far. 
						
						==Add yourself as participant==
						It is important to add yourself as participant before you start working on a task. This helps everyone see who is involved and contributing. 
						Open the task of your choice. Every task page has a '''task attributes''' section. This section contains an attribute named '''participants'''. 
						Click on this row to open the edit mode. Type your '''<code>&#60;firstname lastname&#62;</code>''' and press enter to confirm your participation. 
						If you want to remove yourself click on the red delete button next to the name.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Participating_Overview.png|450px]]
						[[File:Docu_Participating_Edit.png|375px]]
						
						==Add Content==
						After you have added yourself as participant you can start adding content to the task page. Click on '''edit''' on the top of the page.
						The page editor opens and shows the current page content. Note that even task pages that appear empty already have content generated by the system. 
						This is shown on the example below.
						'''<span style="color:red;">It is important that all system generated content remains untouched</span>'''. You can add your content between the '''<code>[ [Category:Task] ]</code>''' line and before 
						'''<code>{{#set ... }}</code>'''.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Participating_EditContent.png|375px]]
						
						==Set Progress==
						After you have added content to the task page, you can adjust the progress on the task to reflect how much of it has been completed.  
						Go to the line that has the '''progress''' attribute and edit the percentage shown.						<br/><br/>		
						[[File:Docu_Participating_SetProgress.png|375px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Hint:''' A lock next to the progress attribute indicates that the system adjusts the progress automatically.
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Person Page">
						<content>
						A person page contains all relevant information regarding a contributor to the wiki. Every person page has a person icon before the '''person's name'''. 
						The next section lists the '''[[#Person Expertise|person's expertise]]'''. After that, all '''[[#Person Tasks|tasks where the person is owner or participant]]''' are listed. <br/><br/>  
						[[File:Docu_Person_PageCutted.png|450px]]
						
						==Person Expertise==
						The Person Expertise section shows expertise keywords for the person. Each expertise keyword is shown with a grey rectangle. 
						Every expertise has a number which indicates how many of the person's tasks have this expertise.
						
						===Highlight Related Tasks===
						Each expertise can be hovered to see which tasks shown in the person page have this expertise. All tasks which have the selected 
						expertise remain, while all others are faded out.<br/><br/>						
						[[File:Docu_Person_ExpertiseHover.png|300px]]				
						
						===Edit Expertise===
						Additional expertise keywords can be specified within the edit mode. By clicking on any expertise you can open the edit mode. 
						Type the new expertise and press enter to confirm. By clicking on the red cross you can delete an expertise keyword.<br/><br/>	
						[[File:Docu_Person_ExpertiseEdit.png|400px]]	
						
						==Person Tasks==
						The person task section lists all person tasks grouped in three categories. First all '''current tasks''' are listed, then 
						all '''future tasks''', and then all '''completed tasks'''. Every task has an icon which shows the 
						current '''task state'''. The task name is highlighted in bold. Next to the task name is a small icon with one or several persons 
						to indicate whether you are the '''owner''' or a '''participant''' respectively. Below the name the most salient status information is shown. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Person_Task.png|300px]]
						
						===Highlight Related Expertise===
						Most tasks are associated with a set of expertise keywords. Move the mouse over a task to see which expertise keywords are associated with that task.<br/>
						[[File:Docu_Person_TaskHover.png|300px]]
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Basic Task States">
						<content>
						This page explains representation of the most common task states. More advanced task states are explained in the section 
						'''[[Extended Task States| extended task states]]'''. Tasks can be '''[[#Underspecified Tasks|underspecified tasks]]''' 
						or '''[[#Fully specified Tasks| fully specified tasks]]'''.  At the end of this page we include a diagram to illustrate how the task state changes over time.
						<!--Every task state have a '''active''' and '''passive''' representation.
						Active representations are explained here. Passive representations visualized as fade out active representation.--><br/><br/>
												
						==Underspecified Tasks==
						Tasks are underspecified when important information is missing, such as the start date or the owner (these are '''mandatory attributes'''). 
						All underspecified tasks are shown
						with rings. The green portion of the ring represents the progress in adding the mandatory task attributes. Mandatory attributes 
						are the task '''Type''', '''Progress''', '''Start date''', '''Target date''' and the '''Owner'''. 
						Tasks missing other attributes such as '''Participants''' and '''Expertise''' are not considered underspecified, so they do not affect the ring symbol. 
						
						===Task created===
						<table>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalCreated.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
									This is the first task state after creation. A wiki page with the task name exists, but no mandatory attributes have been specified.
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>			
						</table>
						===Task Specification in Progress===
						<table>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalMetaDataInProgress.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										A task has some attributes specified. The proportion of attributes specified is visualized in 
										this state.
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>			
						</table>						
						
						==Fully specified Tasks==
						Tasks are fully specified when all mandatory attributes have been set. This state is shown with a pie chart. 
						The grey part shows work left to be done as a percentage, and the green shows the work that has already been done. The colors can differ depending on 
						the task state as we explain next.
						
						===Task in Progress===
						<table>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalMetaDataComplete.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										 Tasks not yet completed but that have all mandatory attributes. 									
									</p>
								</td>							
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalInProgress.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										Certain progress has been made on the task.
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalInProgressWithChildOverdue.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										[[#Task Overdue|Overdue]] subtasks are indicated with a orange point on the bottom right. 
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>
						</table>						
						
						===Task Overdue===
						<table>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalOverdue.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										The task is not yet completed, but the target date is passed. It can also indicate that a subtask is not finished 
										and the task target date is already passed.
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>			
						</table>							
						
						===Task Completed===
						<table>
							<tr>
								<td>[[File:Docu_StateNormalCompleted.png|30px]]</td>
								<td style="vertical-align:middle">
									<p style="margin:0px;">
										The task is completed and its progress is set to 100 percent. The progress calculation depends on the task type.
									</p>
								</td>
							</tr>			
						</table>	
						
						==Typical state progression of tasks==
						[[File:Docu_StateSimpleProcess.png|450px]]
						</content>
					</page>
				</subpages>
			</page>
			<page title="Contribute as Owner">
				<content>		
					This page documents how to contribute to tasks as their owner. You can select one 
					of the following topics to learn how to contribute as a task owner.
					<table>
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_Create.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Create Task]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn about creating new tasks.
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_Alert.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Task Alert]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn about using the task alert.	
							</td>
						</tr>	
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_Organize.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Organize Tasks]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn about organizing existing tasks. This includes renaming tasks, moving tasks, and deleting tasks.
							</td>
						</tr>	
						<tr>
							<td>[[File:Docu_States.png|50px]]</td>
							<td style="vertical-align:middle">
								'''[[Extended Task States]]''' <br/>
								Here you can learn everything about how task states change over time.
							</td>
						</tr>	
					</table>								
				</content>
				<subpages>
					<page title="Create Task">
						<content>
						This page explains how to '''[[#Create Plain Task|create new tasks]]''' and how to 
						'''[[#Add Task Attributes|add task attributes]]'''. It also explains how to '''[[#Add Additional Properties|add additional properties]]''' 
						and how to '''[[#Add Content| add new content]]'''. Remember to login before creating an new task.
						
						==Create Plain Task==
						A new '''root task''' can be created via the '''[[Exploring Tasks#Task Explorer|Task Explorer]]''' and '''new subtasks''' via the 
						'''[[Exploring Tasks#Subtask Explorer|Subtask Explorer]]'''. Start by clicking on the plus button, an input 
						field appears. Type the name of the new task and press enter to confirm. If you have an expertise keyword selected when you create a new 
						root task, then the system will automatically add that expertise keyword to the task.  If the My Tasks tab is selected when you add a new task, the system will set you up as its owner.<br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_CreateTask1.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_CreateTask2.png|200px]]<br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_CreateTask3.png|450px]]<br/>
						
						==Add Task Attributes==						
						Task '''attributes''' are useful to describe tasks. Attributes marked with '''M''' are '''mandatory''', because they are 
						used by the wiki to organize tasks. 
						'''Attributes''' can be added after a task is created. Click on a attribute row to enable editing. 
						The following sub sections explain all task attributes in more detail. Different [[#Attributes States| attribute states]] are explained in the last section. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttributes.png|450px]]						
						
						===Task Types===
						Task types are used by the system to estimate '''[[#Progress|progress]]''' of tasks in different ways. The framework provides three 
						different task types that imply a hierarchical order.  We use a different shade of green in the task state icon for every task type.
						 
						'''Different task types:'''
						<table style="font-size:smaller;">
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#b7db7b; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>High</b></td>
								<td>
									High abstraction level &#8594; High uncertainty in the estimation of task completion.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">Tasks at a high level for a project may have uncertain duration and end date.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#76b531; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>Medium</b></td>
								<td>
									Medium abstraction level &#8594; Medium uncertainty in the estimation of task completion.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">Tasks representing an activity within a project may be split into several subtasks.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#448200; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>Low</b></td>
								<td>
									Low abstraction level &#8594; Low uncertainty in the estimation of task completion.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">Small, well-defined tasks that can be accomplished in a short time period.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
						</table>	
						<br/>
						'''Task hierarchy examples:'''<br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_Type_HierachySample.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Rules for assigning a task type:'''<br/>
						<b>							 
							<span style="font-size:smaller;">
								<span style="color:#b7db7b; font-size:17px;">�</span>High &#8804;
								<span style="color:#76b531; font-size:17px;">�</span>Medium &#8804;
								<span style="color:#448200; font-size:17px;">�</span>Low
							</span>
						</b><br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_Type_SelectType.png|400px]]<br/><br/>
						
						===Progress===
						The progress of a task indicates how much work has been done as a percentage. The system automatically estimates 
						progress depending on the '''[[#Task Type|task type]]'''.
						The level of progress of high-level tasks is estimated based on the start date, today's date and
						the target date. For medium-level tasks, the progress is estimated by aggregating the progress of their subtasks as an average. The progress of low-level
						task is always set by the user. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_ProgressCalculation.png|350px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Hint:''' Medium-level tasks will hardly ever get done unless you decompose them into clear smaller low-level subtasks.<br/>
						
						===Time Interval===
						This section summarizes the meta data attributes '''start date''' and '''target date'''. The time intervals for a task and its subtasks  
						follow a strictly hierarchical approach. Therefore, the start and target dates of any task must be within the time interval of
						the parent task. This leads to a time funnel illustrated on the figure below. If any inconsistency occurs 
						it will be highlighted in yellow in the Task Status and the Timeline View.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_TimeFunnel.png|300px]]
						
						===Owner===
						A task '''owner''' is responsible for coordinating the activities for a task and overseeing its completion. 
						Therefore the system expects exactly one owner. All task which are assigned to you as owner are shown in your My Task 
						tab and on your [[Person Page|person page]].  Persons who have a wiki account are shown in blue and linked to their wiki page.
						Persons who do not have an account are shown in red. See [[#Participant|participant]] example.  <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_Owner.png|100px]]
						
						===Participant===
						Every task can have many participants. These persons may represent a team or just a working group for the task. Participants
						who have a wiki account are shown in blue and linked to their [[Person Page|person page]].
						Persons who do not have an account are shown in red. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_Participants.png|200px]]
						
						===Expertise===
						Expertise keywords are used to indicate the knowledge you might need to accomplish a task. Several expertise keywords can be assigned to a given task. You can easily recognize 
						expertise keywords in any page by the grey rectangle around them. The [[Exploring Tasks#Task Explorer|task explorer]] allows to search for tasks with certain expertise keywords.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddAttribute_Expertise.png|140px]]
						
						===Attributes States===
						The task attribute state is represented with different colors for the attribute icons.
						<table style="font-size:smaller;">
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#cccccc; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>Not defined</b></td>
								<td>
									No value for this attribute set.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">You can set this attribute value.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#b7db7a; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>Valid</b></td>
								<td>
									A valid value for this attribute is set.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">You can modify the value.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
							<tr>
								<td><span style="color:#fed800; font-size:17px;">�</span><b>Inconsistent</b></td>
								<td>
									A value that is inconsistent with the parent task is set.<br/>
									<span style="font-style:italic;">You can change this value or value of the parent task. Hover over icon to get more instructions.</span>
								</td>
							</tr>
						</table>	
						
						==Add Additional Attributes==
						Adding additional custom attributes allow to structure any page content with '''key value''' pairs. These additional attributes help to make page content searchable by
						custom properties. You can add a new property by clicking on the add button. Click on the cross to remove a certain property.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_AddProperty.png|550px]]<br/>
						'''Hint:''' You can add more attributes with the same name and a different value. E.g. this content could be led by two persons.<br/>
						
						==Add Content==
						After you have added some attributes, you can start adding content to the task page. Click on '''edit''' in the top navigation.
						The page editor opens and shows the current page content. Note that even empty pages may already have content generated by the system. This is shown on the example below.
						'''<span style="color:red;">It is important that all system-generated content remains untouched</span>'''. You can add your content between the '''<code>[ [Category:Task] ]</code>''' line and before 
						'''<code>{{#set ... }}</code>'''.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Create_EditContent.png|550px]]
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Task Alert">
						<content>
						The '''Task Alert'''  shows all tasks which are overdue. A task is overdue when the target date is past by and the progress is not 100 percent. 
						On the top of the wiki, a '''red alert bell''' indicates that you have at least one overdue task. Hover or click on it and all overdue tasks are listed. With one more 
						click you can open the task page. 
						You can modify the [[Create Task#Time Interval|target date]] if you need more time.
						As you do more work, change the [[Create Task#Progress|progress]] until the task is 100 percent completed. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_TaskAlert.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Hint:''' The alert bell is only visible for users who are logged in. 
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Organize Tasks">
						<content>
						This page documents how to reorganize tasks in the wiki. All reorganizing actions can be done within the 
						[[Exploring Tasks#Task Explorer|Task Explorer]] and the [[Exploring Tasks#Subtask Explorer|Subtask Explorer]].
						You can [[#Rename Task|rename tasks]], [[#Move Task|move tasks]] or [[#Delete Task|delete tasks]]. All possible
						actions for a task are visible with a right click on a selected task.<br/>
						<br/>								
						'''Important:''' <i>Use only operations to create, rename, move and delete tasks which are described here. 
						The usage of default media wiki operations like delete or move task pages will lead to an inconsistent state.</i>
						
						==Rename Task==
						You can '''rename''' a task with a right click on any selected task. Select rename from the pull-down menu, change the name and press enter to confirm the change. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_Rename.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Hint:''' With a click on any other task you can abort the action.
						
						==Move Task==
						Moving task works similar to the file explorer in the desktop. First you need to ''cut'' a task by doing a right click to open the menu and selecting cut. 
						In the next step you need to define the destination. Do a right click on the new parent task and select ''paste''. With this
						step the move action is complete.<br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveCutPaste.png|450px]]<br/><br/>
						'''Hint:''' The following steps are optional.<br/><br/>
						Tasks are hierarchically organized, therefore subtasks should follow the restrictions of their parent tasks. 
						This means a task target date should be not later than the parent [[Create Task#Time Interval|task target date]]. 
						Similar restrictions exist for the [[Create Task#Task Types|task type]]. 
						If any inconsistency occurs task are highlighted in yellow. The following steps explain how to make tasks consistent.  <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveProblem.png|650px]]<br/><br/>
						The following figure illustrates the inconsistency problem of target dates on a conceptual level. After moving the task, the target date is 
						inconsistent and it is shown in yellow. There are two approaches to solve this problem. You can postpone the target date of the current task or
						you postpone the target date of the parent task. <br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveSolutions.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						This figure illustrates changing the tasks target date.<br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveSolutiona.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						The figure below illustrates changing the parent task's target date.<br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveSolutionb.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						
						'''Hint:''' The task warnings automatically disappear when the tasks are consistent again.<br/><br/>
						
						==Move Task to Toplevel==
						Tasks cannot be [[#Move Task|moved]] by cut and paste to top-level.  Instead, 
						select a task by right clicking and select '''ToToplevel''' in the pull-down menu. <br/><br/>
						[[File:Docu_MoveToToplevel.png|450px]]<br/><br/>
						
						==Delete Task==
						Every task can be deleted with a right click and selecting delete from the pull-down menu. Deleting a task means also deleting all of its 
						subtasks. The system will as you to confirm that you want to delete all these tasks.
						[[File:Docu_Delete.png|550px]]<br/><br/>
						
						'''Hint:''' This action can not be undone easily.
						</content>
					</page>
					<page title="Extended Task States">
						<content>
						This page extends the '''[[#Basic Task States|basic task state]]''' documentation. Organizing tasks, especially moving tasks, can cause 
						inconsistent states. The basic task states are extended with warnings to visualize the inconsistency. We have two different warnings. 
						'''Warnings''' regarding the task itself are indicated by '''yellow colored''' status icons.
						'''Subtask warnings''' indicate that at least one subtasks has an inconsistent state. 
						This is represented with an small additional '''yellow triangle''' on the bottom. left of the task icon.
						<br/><br/>
						Possible task states and their successors:<br/>
						[[File:Docu_ExtendedState_Process.png|550px|Extended Task States]]
						
						
												 <!-- Task '''meta data''' is necessary to process the task by the framework.All task status icons are created
						based on this meta data. The following figure illustrates this more detailed. Basically we differ tasks on 
						'''[[Simple Task States|meta level]]''' and tasks on '''[[Simple Task States|content level]]'''. The '''progress on the meta level'''
						depends on the '''percentage of completed meta data'''. The green cycle part represents the completed meta data and 
						the grey part represents the left meta data part. On '''content level''' the progress depends on the '''tasks content'''. 
						All content level states are represented by a pie chart. The green part indicated the completed part in percentage.
						For the following subsections its important to know that the whole framework is designed as top-down approach. This means
						decision are made on the top level and break down on lower level decisions.<br/><br/>
						[[File:TaskMetaDataProgress.png|400px]]-->
						</content>
					</page>
				</subpages>
			</page>
		</subpages>
	</page>
</documentation>